John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Statements of Condition, RG 2 FA1796
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Statements of Condition, RG 2
1975-2008
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation
FA1796
2.28 Cubic Feet (6 containers)
Scope and Contents
Record Group 2, Statements of Condition, consists of the Foundation's Annual Reports. The early reports created between 1975 and 1981 contain only general information about the Foundation. But beginning in 1982, the annual reports provide insight into the Foundation's purpose, philosophy, and grant-making activities.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted.
- Annual Reports, 1975-2008; 1; 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  The annual reports from 1975 to 1981 are brief, listing only categories of grants and the amounts given (i.e., Journalism: $25,000). After 1982, the reports provide more detailed information about the grants given each year, including the names of grantees and the specific amount of the grant. These later reports also include a Chairman's Letter, the Foundation's statement of purpose, history, and the background and mission of each of the programs, as well as financial information about the Foundation and its assets. There is also an index of grants, a list of grants by program and type, instructions on how to apply for a grant, feature stories about grant recipients, and photographs of Trustees, Officers and staff.
  - Annual Reports, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
    Correspondence re: creation of an annual report, types of information to be included; also draft of chairman's letter.
  - Annual Reports, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
    Annual report of the Foundation, published annually in the spring of the following year. Contains information on programs, priorities, people and grants. Multiple copies of each year retained.
  - Annual Reports, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Annual Reports, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Annual Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Annual Report, "A New Approach", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Annual Report, "Knight's September 11th Fund", 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Annual Report, "What is Freedom?", 2002 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Annual Report, "We the People", 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Annual Reports, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 3-7)
  - Annual Report, 2007-2008 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Annual report of the Foundation, entitled "A Progress Report, 2007 - 2008". This is a brochure, not the full report published in previous years. The document is "a symbol of Knight Foundation's transformation into a 21st century organization. It is a slimmer, more succinct version of our traditional annual report.... You'll find this and more more content on the web .... It's a trend we expect will continue, until all of the information we provide to our constituents is digital...." Multiple copies.